( WIND HOWLING )
( WIND CONTINUES HOWLING )
( PIANO PLAYING )
( ALL CHATTERING LOUDLY )
MAN : Twenty .
You hear about Mrs. Mason 's little Willy ?
Sent him to school and found him
buried 10-foot-deep in a snow drift .
How did they get him out ?
Brought the fire engine round .
Put the hose pipe in , pumped it backwards and sucked him out .
( ALL LAUGHING )
( LAUGHING CONTINUES )
( PEOPLE APPLAUDING )
( PIANO PLAYING )
( ALL LAUGHING )
Fifty . Well done .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
( WIND HOWLING )
( LAUGHING STOPS )
I want a room and a fire .
Jenny ?
Hello ?
There 's a gent here who wants a room and a fire .
Want a room ?
I said a room .
We ain 't got none ready , not at this time of year .
We don 't usually have folks stop in , except in the summer .
You can get one ready .
Certainly , sir . Minnie !
Yes ?
I want a private sitting room too .
Certainly , sir .
Will you come through , sir ? This way , sir .
It 's the coldest winter we 've had down here for years .
They 've had all the sheep and the cows in for a fortnight now .
Poor things . They can 't get a blade of green grass .
You may be near-sighted , but you can 't be deaf and dumb as well .
( BLOWING )
Could I take your coat and hat , sir ,
and give them a nice dry in the kitchen ?
No .
I prefer to keep them on .
Very good , sir . The room will be warm soon .
I 've got some luggage at the station . How can I have it sent ?
I 'll get it brought over tomorrow , sir . Are you going to stay a bit ?
Yes .
Is there no way of getting it tonight ?
Oh , not tonight , sir .
Very well .
Bring me some food .
Right away , sir .
If you ask me , he 's a criminal flying from justice .
Go on . He 's snow-blind , that 's what he is .
Has to wear goggles to save his eyes .
Anyway , you be careful and lock your money up .
A bottle of Bass , Herbert .
Here you are , dear .
I hope he 'll be a bit more communicative this time .
( KNOCKING )
Your supper , sir .
Is there a key to that door ?
A key , sir ?
I haven 't ever seen one .
I don 't think there was one when we came here .
I want to be left alone and undisturbed .
I 'll see that no one disturbs you , sir .
( DOOR CLOSING )
Here 's the mustard , ma 'am .
You 'll be the death of me with your slowness .
Here , you let me take the gentleman 's supper in and forget the mustard !
And him wanting to be left alone !
( MUTTERING )
There she goes again ...
I told you not to disturb me .
It 's only the mustard , sir . I forgot it .
I 'm sorry .
Thank you .
Have you been motoring on them slippery roads , sir ?
You can take my overcoat and dry it .
Very good , sir .
Leave the hat .
Yes , sir .
Bandages right up to the top of his head , all round his ears .
Any blood ?
No , no blood .
Looks like some kind of horrible accident .
Bumped his head on the prison wall getting over .
Father .
I wish you 'd leave me alone , Flora , when I 'm working .
I can 't bear it . We 've got to do something .
Do something ? What about ?
About Jack .
Oh , he 'll come back . Don 't you worry .
Father , please put that horrid thing down and listen .
It 's nearly a month now without a word .
But the note he left was quite clear .
He said we might not hear for a while .
It 's a good thing to go away when you 're finishing a difficult experiment .
What kind of experiment is it , Father ?
Something of his own .
I had a terrible feeling last night .
I felt he was in desperate trouble .
Hello , Kemp . Flora 's worried about Griffin .
I don 't wonder . I should 've thought at least he could drop a line .
It 's a queer thing .
It certainly is , considering he was in your employ .
He had my permission to carry out his own experiments in his spare time .
And clear off when he liked , for as long as he liked ?
What does it matter , if he 's in trouble ?
( FLORA SOBBING )
I 've got the car outside . It 'll give you a rest to come for a run .
Do you think there are any papers in his room to help us ?
Surely he must have arranged where he was going .
There may be letters .
He left a heap of burnt papers in his fireplace , that 's all .
He was so strange those last few days before he went ...
So excited and strung up . And yet he wouldn 't say a word to explain .
I 've never seen him like it before .
He was always so keen to tell me about his experiments .
He meddled in things men should leave alone .
What do you mean ?
Your father 's a scientist , Flora .
He 's discovered more about preserving food than any man living .
Jack and I were employed to help him .
That 's a plain , straightforward job .
It 's not romantic ,
but it saves hundreds of deaths and thousands of stomach aches .
What did you mean about " things men should leave alone " ?
He worked in secret .
He kept a lot of stuff locked in a cupboard in his laboratory .
He never opened that cupboard until he 'd barred the door and drawn the blinds .
Straightforward scientists have no need for barred doors and drawn blinds .
He cares nothing for you , Flora .
He 'll never care about anything but test tubes and chemicals .
How can he go away like this without a word ?
Flora , dear ... Please , darling , let me tell you how I feel .
I can 't work or sleep until I know .
Oh , leave me alone ! How can you ?
( SOBBING CONTINUES )
Damn ! You annoy me .
There 's a way back , you fool .
There must be a way back .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
What is it ? JENNY : Your lunch , sir .
Take it away .
You don 't want it cold , do you ?
Do you suppose that I 'm going to carry trays
backwards and forwards all day ?
Lunch is at 1 : 00 , and it 's 1 : 00 now !
Get out !
( TRAY CRASHING )
( SCREAMING )
He 's not gonna stay under this roof , not another hour .
Crashed the tray out of me hand and swore at me .
Turned my best sitting room into a chemist 's shop .
Spilled it on the carpets .
And him a week behind with his money .
Go and tell him if he ain 't packed up and gone in half an hour ,
we 'll have the law in to turn him out .
And take him his bill !
Three pounds ten . And see you get it before you come out .
Go on !
Let 's leave him a bit , Jenny , till he cools off .
Go on . Do it now . Him and his goggles and his chemist 's shop .
If you don 't kick him out , I 'm clearing out meself , and that 's the truth .
And I mean it this time .
( SIGHS )
And a whole day 's work ruined ,
by a foolish , ignorant woman !
There must be a way back .
God knows there 's a way back .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
If only they 'd leave me alone .
Look here , mister . We can 't have this no more .
You 've broken the wife 's best china .
You 're a week behind with the rent .
You 've got to pack up and go .
I 'm expecting some money , Mr. Hall .
I 'll pay you directly it comes .
You said that last week , and it hasn 't come yet .
I came here for quiet and secrecy .
I 'm carrying out a difficult experiment .
I must be left alone . It 's vital .
It 's life and death that I should be left alone .
You don 't understand .
I understand all right .
You don 't pay .
And what 's more , you 're driving folks away from our house .
Mr. Hall , I 've had a serious accident .
It 's disfigured me , affected my eyes .
I don 't mean that . I mean the way you carry on ,
throwing things about on the carpets and swearing .
It 's no good , mister . You 've got to go .
I implore you to let me stay . I beg of you .
The wife says if you don 't go , she is . So it 's got to be you .
Come on . I 'll help you to get this stuff packed up .
Leave that alone and get out of here !
Look here ! Is this my house or yours ?
( GRUNTING )
( YELLING )
What are you doing ? Help !
( GRUNTING )
( GROANING )
Help ! Help ! Police !
( SOBBING )
( ALL CHATTERING )
He 's a raving lunatic !
( SOBBING CONTINUES )
Go and get a policeman .
Please don 't cry , now . He 'll be all right . He 's not harmed .
He 's all right . Please don 't cry .
( SCREAMING )
( CHATTERING )
Shut up !
Please don 't cry .
Come on , Jaffers .
What 's all this ?
It 's the stranger with the goggles . He 's gone mad .
He assaulted Mrs. Hall and nearly killed her husband .
( ALL CHATTERING )
Where is he ?
He 's upstairs in the sitting room .
He 's in there in the sitting room . He 's homicidal .
( SCREAMS )
Let that down .
( CRYING LOUDLY )
Keep back , you kids there .
Go on out .
What 's all this ?
Keep back there .
Keep back ? Me ? Do you know who you 're talking to ?
I give you a last chance to leave me alone .
Give me a last chance ?
You 've committed assault , that 's what you 've done .
You can come along to the station with me .
Come along , now . Come quietly . Unless you want me to put the handcuffs on .
Stop where you are . You don 't know what you 're doing .
I know what I 'm doing all right . Come on .
MAN 1 : Get hold of him . MAN 2 : Lock him up .
All right , you fools .
You 've brought it on yourselves .
Everything would 've come right if you 'd only left me alone .
You 've driven me near madness with your peering through the keyholes ...
And peeping through the curtains .
And now you 'll suffer for it !
You 're crazy to know who I am , aren 't you ?
All right , I 'll show you !
There 's a souvenir for you .
And one for you !
I 'll show you who I am and what I am !
( LAUGHING MANIACALLY )
Look . He 's all eaten away .
How do you like that , eh ?
( ALL CLAMORING )
( JACK LAUGHING )
( LAUGHING CONTINUES )
It was horrible .
What 's wrong ?
Well , Jaffers , what do you think ?
He 's invisible .
That 's what 's the matter with him .
If he gets the rest of them clothes off ,
we 'll never catch him in a thousand years .
Come on .
They 've asked for it , the country bumpkins .
This will give them a bit of a shock .
Something to write home about .
A nice bedtime story for the kids , too , if they want it .
( LAUGHING )
Put the handcuffs on .
How can I handcuff a bloomin ' shirt ?
Quick , get hold of him !
( LAUGHING )
( LAUGHING CONTINUES )
JACK : Are you satisfied now , you fools ?
It 's easy , really , if you 're clever .
A few chemicals mixed together , that 's all .
And flesh and blood and bone just fade away .
A little of this injected under the skin of the arm every day for a month .
An invisible man can rule the world !
Nobody will see him come . Nobody will see him go .
He can hear every secret . He can rob and rape and kill !
( LAUGHING )
Not if he can 't get no further than this room , he won 't .
Here , shut that door .
Now , then , you 'd better come along quietly .
( JACK LAUGHING )
MAN : Look out ! Mind that window !
( JACK LAUGHS )
JACK : You think I 'd escape like a common criminal ?
You need a lesson .
I think I 'll throttle you .
( CHOKING )
Let go of me ! Let go !
( GRUNTS )
JACK : You must be made to understand what I can do .
( MEN GRUNTING )
MAN : Hey , look out !
( RAPID FOOTSTEPS )
( SCREAMING )
Hey , whoa !
( MUGS SHATTERING )
Hey ! Hey !
Let him go ! Look out !
( ALL CHATTERING )
JACK : I 'm afraid I need this bicycle . ( CHUCKLES )
MAN : He stole my bike !
Stop him ! Stop him !
JACK : Here 's your blooming bicycle .
You can do what you like with it .
How 's that for a hair brush , George Henry ?
( SCREAMS )
Good morning , grandfather . How do you do ?
( CHUCKLING )
We do our part .
( CRYING ) ( WHIMPERING )
Mama , never mind the plated goods . Give me the diamonds .
On the gospel , it 's the truth . He tried to strangle me , sir .
Where are you speaking from , Jaffers ?
Lion 's Head Inn , eh ?
Did you say an invisible man ?
Well , look here . You put more water in it next time .
He won 't believe me . You tell him .
Mr. Hall speaking . The constable 's telling the truth , all right .
MAN : Invisible man special ! Horrible murder in Iping ! Invisible man ...
Not the slightest clue .
I didn 't expect there would be .
That 's where the clues are . He wasn 't leaving anything to chance .
Griffin was never the man for secrets . He came to me with everything .
He kept a lot of stuff locked in here .
I came in one evening when he wasn 't expecting me .
He was standing here by this cupboard . It was full of instruments .
When he saw me , he slammed the door and turned the key .
Hmm .
You say he brought a packing case up here ?
The night before he disappeared ,
I heard him hammering , packing everything up .
Here 's something , Kemp .
What is it ? Bad news ?
It 's only a rough note , a list of chemicals .
And the last on the list is monocaine .
Monocaine ? What is monocaine ?
Monocaine 's a terrible drug .
I never heard of it .
You wouldn 't , Kemp . It 's never used now .
I didn 't know it was even made .
It 's a drug that 's made from a flower that 's grown in India .
It draws color from everything it touches .
Years ago they tried it for bleaching cloth .
They gave it up because it destroyed the material .
That doesn 't sound terrible .
Yes , I know . But it does something else , Kemp .
It was tried out on some poor animal ... A dog , I believe .
It was injected under the skin ,
and it turned the dog dead white
like a marble statue .
Is that so ?
Yes , and it also sent it raving mad .
You surely don 't think ...
I only pray to God that Griffin hasn 't been meddling with this ghastly stuff .
He 'd never touch a thing with madness in it .
He might not know .
I found that experiment in an old German book , just by chance .
The English books only described the bleaching power .
They were printed before the German experiment .
What are we going to do , Doctor ?
I think we must tell the police that Griffin 's disappeared .
But only that he 's disappeared .
I put you on your honor , Kemp , not to breathe a word of this to anyone .
Shall I go down to the police station with you ?
It 's all right , Kemp . I 'll go tonight when Inspector Lane 's on duty .
I 'll run along back home , then .
Good night .
Good night , Kemp .
( PIANO PLAYING ON RADIO )
MAN : ( OVER RADIO ) This is the national station
broadcasting this evening 's news .
Remarkable story from country village .
Police and doctors are investigating an astonishing story
told this afternoon by the people of the village of Iping .
It appears that a mysterious disease has broken out
infecting a large number of the inhabitants .
It takes the form of a delusion
that an invisible man is living among them .
Several people have been seriously injured ,
probably through fighting among themselves
in the belief the their opponent is an invisible man .
The whole village is in a state of panic , and everyone ...
JACK : And everyone deserves the fate that 's coming to them .
Panic , death , things worse than death .
Don 't be afraid , Kemp . It 's me , Griffin .
Jack Griffin . How are you , my friend ?
( SHIVERING )
I 'm frozen with cold .
Dead tired . Thank God for a fire .
( GASPS )
Sit down , you fool . Let 's have a decent fire .
Did you hear me ? Sit down .
Unless you want me to knock your brains out .
Sit down !
I want you to listen carefully , Kemp .
I 've been through hell today . I want food and sleep .
But before we sleep , there 's work to do . May I have a cigarette ?
You always were a dirty little card , Kemp .
You 're frightened out of your wits , aren 't you ?
Oh , it 's no good talking like this .
Have you got a good long surgical bandage ?
Good . And a pair of dark glasses ?
Right . Go and get them at once .
Let me have a dressing gown , and pajamas , and a pair of gloves .
You 'll feel better if you can see me , won 't you ?
Come on . We 've no time to waste .
( DOOR SLAMMING )
You 'll find some pajamas in that room .
Here are the gloves and bandages .
I 'll bring you the glasses .
Thank you . Don 't be long .
JACK : Put them on the table .
Now go down and draw the blinds in your sitting room .
Are we alone in the house ?
Yes . Good .
All right , go now .
If you raise a finger against me , you 're a dead man .
I 'm strong , and I 'll strangle you . Understand ?
Wait for me downstairs .
JACK : The sitting room , I said , Kemp .
And if you try and escape by the window , I shall follow you .
And no one in the world can save you .
Here comes the inspector now .
Get up .
Nice fool you 've made of me . I 've got reports for ten miles around .
Not a sign of anything . I 'll tell you what I think of your invisible man .
It 's a hoax .
Good business for the saloon bar , Mr. Hall ?
Suppose I 'd break my neck to sell a gallon of beer ?
I 'll have an inquiry right now .
Bring in everybody who thinks they saw or heard anything .
I 'll get at the bottom of this before the night 's out .
CONSTABLE : Here . Get those tables together .
Now , Kemp .
Now , then , we can talk as man to man .
Sit down .
One day I 'll tell you everything . There 's no time now .
I began five years ago in secret ,
working all night , every night , right into the dawn .
A thousand experiments , a thousand failures .
And then , at last , the great , wonderful day .
But , Griffin , it 's ghastly .
The great , wonderful day .
The last little mixture of drugs .
I couldn 't stay here any longer , Kemp .
I couldn 't let you see me slowly fading away .
So I packed up and went to a little village for secrecy and quiet ,
to finish the experiment and complete the antidote ,
the way back to visible man again .
I meant to come back just as I was when you saw me last .
The fools wouldn 't let me work in peace .
I had to teach them a lesson .
But why ... Why do it , Griffin ?
Just a scientific experiment at first . That 's all .
To do something no other man in the world had done .
But there 's more to it than that , Kemp . I know now .
It came to me suddenly . The drugs I took seemed to light up my brain .
Suddenly I realized the power I held .
The power to rule , to make the world grovel at my feet .
( LAUGHS )
We 'll soon put the world right now , Kemp .
You and I.
I ? You mean ...
I must have a partner , Kemp .
A visible partner to help me in the little things .
You 're my partner , Kemp .
We 'll begin with a reign of terror ,
a few murders here and there .
Murders of great men , murders of little men ,
just to show we make no distinction .
We might even wreck a train or two .
Just these fingers around a signalman 's throat .
That 's all .
Griffin , for heaven 's sake !
You want me to take these off ?
No , no .
Very well , then . We 'll make our plans tomorrow .
Tonight we have a small job to do .
Go and get your car out , Kemp .
Why ? Where are we going ?
Back to the village I left this morning .
I came away without my notebooks .
They contain all the results of my experiments .
I must have them here .
But it 's past 8 : 00 .
It 's only 15 miles . Go now , quickly .
And take a bag with you for the books .
Put a warm rug in the car .
It 's cold outside when you have to go about naked .
JACK : All ready ?
Yes .
JACK : Come on ! Get in !
Where is that rug ? In the back .
I 'm frozen . Cold enough to freeze the icicles off an Eskimo .
We 'll stop in a lane 100 yards from the inn .
I 'll go in and give you the books through the window .
They 'll have a guard .
What can a guard do , you fool ?
I must have those books , Kemp .
I 'll work in your laboratory till I find the antidote .
And sometimes I 'll make you invisible , give me a rest .
I was walkin ' home to my lunch , sir ,
when all of a sudden , something takes hold of me hat and throws it in the pond .
How many drinks did you have on your way home ?
Only a couple , sir . That 's all .
A couple of drinks and a gust of wind . So much for you .
Now , then , about the bicycle .
Where 's the owner of the bicycle ?
Here , sir .
It was pulled clean out of me hands , sir .
Then it went peddling off down the street , all by itself .
JACK : Stop here .
Come on , get out .
Take your bag and walk straight down the street . I 'll guide you .
Wait outside the pub window till the books come out .
Put them in your bag and come back to the car . Then wait for me .
Don 't stare at me , you fool . Look in front of you .
Come on , get a move on !
Here we are , Kemp . In here . ( CHUCKLES )
Here . Stroll up and down as though you were waiting for someone .
Watch for that window to open .
Griffin ? Griffin ? Are you there ?
Who 's that , opened that door ?
It 's them boys again , sir .
( CLICKING TONGUE )
Here , you leave this door alone . It 's private , see ?
We never touched it !
Yes , you did . Go on !
Go on ! Off you go !
Crazies ! Crazies !
( STAIRS CREAKING )
JACK : Here you are , Kemp .
Lies from beginning to end !
I have a good mind to prosecute
the whole lot of you for conspiracy .
I shall announce this evening that the whole thing is a hoax
and you 'll be the laughingstock of the entire country .
He 's here ! The Invisible Man !
( SCREAMING )
( SCREAMING CONTINUES )
( ALL CLAMORING )
( INDISTINCT SHOUTING )
Don 't leave me ! Wait for me ! Don 't leave me ! Wait for me !
( CHOKING )
JACK : A hoax , is it ? All a hoax ?
( GRUNTS )
All a hoax ?
There .
( DOOR CLOSING )
( JACK PANTING )
All right , off you go .
( ENGINE STARTS )
Go for your life too !
JACK : Did you hear some shouting and screaming ?
What was that screaming ?
Had to take some exercise to keep warm .
I killed a stupid little policeman . Smashed his head in .
We start in earnest tomorrow morning , Kemp .
Good evening , Doctor . Good evening .
Is Inspector Lane at the station ? I want a word with him .
Yes , sir ...
Extra special ! Invisible Man slays policeman !
( ALL CHATTERING EXCITEDLY )
( CHATTERING CONTINUES )
BOY : Evening paper ! Get your paper !
Nasty business , this .
It 's a conjuring trick , that 's what it is .
I saw a fellow make a peanut disappear once .
There are one or two things you must understand , Kemp .
I must always remain in hiding for an hour after meals .
The food is visible inside me until it is digested .
I can only work on fine , clear days .
If I work in the rain , the water can be seen on my head and shoulders .
In a fog , you can see me , like a bubble .
In smoky cities , the soot settles on me ,
until you can see a dark outline .
You must always be near at hand to wipe off my feet .
Even dirt between my fingernails would give me away .
It is difficult , at first , to walk down stairs .
We are so accustomed to watching our feet .
But these are trivial difficulties .
We shall find ways of defeating everything .
You will sleep in the room opposite
and bring me some more food at 8 : 00 .
Good night .
( CLOCK CHIMING )
( DOG BARKING DISTANTLY )
( YAWNING )
( SOBBING )
Now you 'll understand my plans .
You 're in charge of all country east of here , Thompson ,
for 20 miles to the north of the main road .
Very good , sir .
Neville , you take the opposite section to the south .
Stollen , you take charge of the search in the hills .
And Hogan , you 'll take all the villages out to the river .
Right , sir .
Now , we shall comb the country for 20 miles round .
We 've got a terrible responsibility . He 's mad , and he 's invisible .
He may be standing beside us now .
But he 's human , and we shall get him .
We shall have 1000 men out tonight .
Tomorrow we shall have 10,000 volunteers to help them .
There 's a broadcast warning going out at 10 : 30 .
Now , at all costs , we must avoid a panic spreading .
Now get away to your districts at once ,
and send me a note of your headquarters .
And remember , he 'll leave tracks ,
even if he himself is invisible .
( INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING )
MAN : ( OVER RADIO ) I must interrupt the dance music for a moment .
I have an urgent message from police headquarters .
Earlier this evening , we broadcast a report of an invisible man .
The report has now been confirmed .
It appears that an unknown man , by scientific means ,
has made himself invisible .
He has attacked and killed a police inspector and is now at large .
The chief of police appeals to the public for help and assistance .
Those willing to cooperate in the search
are requested to report tomorrow morning to their local station .
The Invisible Man works without clothing . He will have to seek shelter .
You 're requested to lock every door and window
and every outbuilding he may use to hide in .
The police will be glad to receive any suggestions
that will help in capturing the fugitive .
Remember , he 's solid but cannot be seen .
A reward of £ 1,000 will be given to any person ,
whose information leads to his capture .
The police appeal to the public to keep calm
and to admit uniformed search parties to all property .
( DANCE MUSIC RESUMES )
MAN 1 : Bar the windows . WOMAN 1 : Keep the fiend out .
MAN 2 : Lock up the doors . MAN 3 : Take no chances .
Lock the windows .
MAN 4 : Check the building round back .
WOMAN 2 : Lock the door .
MAN 5 : I 've got the doors padlocked .
MAN 6 : I 'll keep him out .
Hello ?
Hello . Get me eashire , 1021 .
( PHONE RINGING )
Hello ? Doctor , listen .
There 's something ghastly . It 's Griffin . He 's come back .
He 's the Invisible Man . He 's asleep in my room .
He 's mad , a raving lunatic ! He 's killed a man tonight .
Listen to me , Kemp . No one but you and I know that it 's Griffin .
I shall come in the morning .
You must come now ! I can 't bear it !
If I come now , he 'll be suspicious and escape .
You must keep him calm and quiet for tonight . I trust you , Kemp .
Who was that , Father ?
It was Kemp .
It was about Jack . I know it . What is it ?
Tell me .
Oh , leave me alone , Flora , please .
I 'm not afraid . Tell me .
Jack Griffin 's come back . He 's at Dr. Kemp 's house now .
Jack Griffin 's the Invisible Man .
Say , is that the police ? Was that £ 1,000 reward right ?
Well , listen , I 've got a way to catch him .
The paper says he threw ink at the man he killed .
Well , you get your own back and squirt ink about with a hosepipe until you hit him .
The ink 'll stick on him , see ? Then you can shoot him .
Is that the police ?
I want to tell you how to catch the Invisible Man .
The paper says it 's gonna be frosty in a day or two .
Well , you watch out when it 's frosty , then you can see his breath .
Police , quickly .
Is this the police ? This is Dr. Kemp .
The Invisible Man is in my house , asleep upstairs .
Come at once . Hurry !
Listen , Doctor , I 've only got five men here .
I 'll want a hundred to surround the house .
Yes , all right , I 'll send them up as soon as possible .
You must leave it to me and Kemp .
We shall work day and night to undo this terrible experiment .
You must let me go to him .
Only when he 's well again .
No , now . I can do more with Jack than you or Dr. Kemp .
But , Flora , he 's not normal . His mind 's unhinged . At present , he 's mad .
I can persuade him to help you .
You 're powerless unless he does .
Get your coat , Father . I 'll be ready in five minutes .
But it 's past midnight .
Wait till the morning .
It 's life or death , Father . You know that .
I 'll go alone , then . Flora .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
Who 's that ? Who 's that ?
Unlock the door , Kemp . Let me in .
What are you doing here , Kemp ?
I couldn 't sleep . I had to get up , come down .
Why did you lock the door ?
I ... I was afraid .
Wouldn 't you be afraid if I were invisible like you ?
There 's no need to be afraid , Kemp .
We 're partners . Bosom friends .
We 've a busy day ahead . You must sleep .
( CAR APPROACHING )
I see . You told the police .
That was why you went downstairs .
No , I ... I didn 't . I swear I didn 't .
Look , it 's not the police . It 's Dr. Cranley and Flora .
Flora .
Why , yes , of course .
I had to tell them you were back , Griffin .
Flora was nearly mad with anxiety .
How could I forget ?
( DOORBELL JINGLING )
KEMP : Shall I let them in ?
Yes , of course you must let them in .
I shall go and prepare myself in my room .
I shall see Flora ... alone .
( DOOR CLOSING )
He knows you 're here . You said he was asleep .
He saw you from the window . He wants to see Flora alone .
No , Flora , don 't .
He 's calm now , quiet .
Jack won 't do me any harm .
I tell you , he 's insane .
It 's for us to cure him , Kemp and I.
Keep away , Flora . I must go to him .
Listen , Doctor , he was a different man
when he saw Flora leave the car .
He won 't hurt her . We must play for time .
Why for time ?
We must prepare things .
If we try and bind him now , he 'll throw us off and escape .
We must take him when he 's asleep and chloroform him . Wait here .
Flora , my darling .
Thank God you 're home , Jack .
I would have come to you at once , Flora , but for this .
How wonderful it is to see you .
How beautiful you look .
( CHUCKLES )
That funny little hat , I always liked . You 've been crying .
I want to help you . Why did you do this ?
For you , Flora .
For me ?
Yes , for you , my darling . I wanted to do something tremendous ,
to achieve what men of science have dreamt of since the world began ,
to gain wealth and fame and honor .
To write my name above the greatest scientists of all time .
I was so pitifully poor .
I had nothing to offer you , Flora .
I was just a poor , struggling chemist .
I shall come back to you , Flora , very soon now .
The secret of invisibility lies there in my books .
I shall work in Kemp 's laboratory till I find a way back .
There is a way back , Flora . And then I shall come to you .
I shall offer my secret to the world , with all its terrible power .
The nations of the world will bid for it . Thousands , millions .
The nation that wins my secret can sweep the world with invisible armies .
Jack , I want you to let my father help you .
You know how clever he is . He 'll work with you day and night ,
until you find that second secret ,
the one that 'll bring you back to us .
Then we 'll have those lovely , peaceful days again ,
out under the trees , after your work in the evening .
Your father ? Clever ? ( CHUCKLES ) You think he can help me ?
He 's got the brain of a tapeworm , a maggot beside mine .
Don 't you see what it means ? Power ! Power to rule !
To make the world grovel at my feet !
Jack , listen to me ! Listen !
My father found a note in your room .
He knows something about monocaine even you don 't know .
It alters you , changes you , makes you feel differently .
Father believes the power of it will go ,
if you know what you 're fighting .
Oh , come and stay with us . Let 's fight this thing out together .
Power , I said !
Power to walk into the gold vaults of the nations ,
into the secrets of kings , into the Holy of Holies ,
power to make multitudes run , squealing in terror
at the touch of my little invisible finger .
Even the moon 's frightened of me , frightened to death .
The whole world 's frightened to death .
( DOGS BARKING )
So , I see . Kemp couldn 't sleep .
He had to go downstairs . He was frightened .
I put my trust in Kemp .
I told him my secret , and he gave me his word of honor .
You must go now , Flora .
I want to help you .
There is nothing for you to do , my dear , except to go .
I shall come back .
I swear I shall come back , because I shall defeat them .
Go now , my dear .
No . I want to stay . You must hide .
Don 't worry . The whole world 's my hiding place .
I can stand out there amongst them in the day or night and laugh at them .
Come along , my darling .
Oh , Father .
Pass on word , link hands all around the house .
Link hands . Link hands .
Stay close together , or he 'll slip under your arm .
Now , boys , forward .
JACK : Thank you , Kemp , for opening the window .
You 're a true friend , Kemp , a man to trust .
I 've no time now , but believe me ,
as surely as the moon will set and the sun will rise ,
I shall kill you tomorrow night .
I shall kill you ,
even if you hide in the deepest cave of the earth .
At 10 : 00 tomorrow night , I shall kill you .
Help ! Help ! He 's here ! He 's here !
Here he comes !
Link hands where you are !
Keep your arms down .
What is it ?
Something smacked my face .
( JACK LAUGHING )
JACK : Naughty boy .
( LAUGHING CONTINUES )
Let go !
What 's the matter with you ?
He pinched my nose .
Now , steady , boys . We 've got him all right this time .
JACK : Good shot .
( JACK LAUGHS )
Get that hat !
Now , then , boys , advance slowly .
It 's all right , he 's unarmed , and we 've got him easy .
Help ! Help ! He 's got me by the feet ! Here he is ! Help !
( SCREAMING )
( POLICE CHATTERING )
It 's the Invisible Man !
He 's got him by the feet . Help him , boys , quick !
( ALL CLAMORING )
Grab him ! Grab him !
( CLAMORING CONTINUES )
Help me !
What do you know about that ?
( WOMAN SCREAMING )
( SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY )
( JACK SINGING )
Here we go gathering nuts in May Nuts in May , nuts in May
Here we go gathering nuts in May On a cold and frosty morning
( WHOOPS )
He threatened to kill me at 10 : 00 tonight .
You must lock me up . Put me in prison .
You 're not the only one in danger , Dr. Kemp .
I 'll see that you have protection .
Now , Dr. Cranley , you 're concealing something from me .
Well ... One moment !
I want you to explain why you and your daughter
were in this house at 2 : 00 this morning ?
Dr. Kemp called me up , he told me the man was here ,
he wanted my help .
Why did he ring you before the police ?
Why did your daughter come too ?
She came to drive the car .
You know who the Invisible Man is , Doctor .
I understand you have another assistant besides Dr. Kemp .
A Dr. Griffin . Where is Dr. Griffin ?
He 's gone away . It is Griffin !
What 's the good of concealing it ?
It 's Griffin , and he 's threatened to murder me !
He may be here now , beside us ,
or in the garden looking through the window ,
or in a corner of my bedroom waiting for me , waiting to kill me !
And you all sit there , doing nothing ! Nothing !
We 've doubled the search party ten miles around Kemp 's house .
There 's nothing to report , sir .
The policeman 's trousers were found in a ditch a mile away . That 's all .
Well , it 's beaten me .
I 'll give £ 1,000 for a practical idea .
He 's roaming the country at will . A madman !
JACK : Here I am . Aren 't you pleased you 've found me ?
( GASPING )
( SCREAMING )
JACK : Would you like to keep him company ?
Stand away ! Keep back !
( TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING )
( PASSENGERS SCREAMING )
Thank you .
MAN : Give me £ 5 worth of silver , please .
BANKER : Yes , sir .
Thank you . Good day .
WOMAN : Good morning , Mr. Simpson . Good morning .
Morning . Morning , sir .
Pleasant day , sir ? Rather nice .
JACK : There you are . A present from the Invisible Man !
Money ! Money ! Money ! Money !
( JACK LAUGHING )
( JACK SINGING )
Up and down the City Road In and out the eagle
That 's the way the money goes Pop goes the weasel
Money , money , money , money , money , money , money !
Twenty men of the search parties have been killed
and a hundred in the train disaster .
The Invisible Man has been reported in a hundred different places .
Now , I appeal to you to help us keep the public calm .
Can you tell us what plans you 've got for capturing him ?
A hundred thousand men are searching and watching .
Yes , I know . But have you any secret means of getting him ?
The police have offered £ 2,000 for the first effective means .
Why not bloodhounds ?
The bloodhounds have lost the scent .
Why not put wet tar on all the roads ,
then chase the black soles of his feet ?
Because he 's not a fool . Now , we 've got one hope , gentlemen ,
but I daren 't say a word of it here .
He may be standing there beside you , listening .
Try and sleep now , my dear .
There 's nothing you can do .
We must just pray that the police can take him without harming him .
( DOOR CLOSING )
( SOBBING )
Stand back , close against the wall .
Now , then , drag that net clear across the room .
Now , everything depends on the way we carry out my plan .
I 'll tell you after we 've made certain he 's not in this room .
Good . Now we 're safe here at last .
Constable , keep an eye on that window .
Now come here , all of you , and sit down .
( CHUCKLING )
Now listen carefully .
We 've got a chance tonight that will never come again .
He 's threatened to murder Dr. Kemp at 10 : 00 .
And from what we know of him , he 'll do his utmost to carry that out .
He 's certain to be near this house ,
watching for some time beforehand .
Now , at 9 : 30 , Dr. Kemp , with a bodyguard of police ,
will leave this house and walk down to the police station .
It 's a natural thing for Dr. Kemp to seek protection .
Now , the Invisible Man is certain to be near .
He 's certain to see what 's happening .
You mean you 're going to use me as a bait ? Yes .
I can 't .
You must . You 'll be perfectly safe .
Safe ? I tell you , he 's not human .
He can go through anything . Prison walls , everything .
Don 't be a fool .
I tell you , I can 't sit in that station waiting .
He 'll kill you , kill you all , then take the keys and come to me .
Very well . If you 're afraid of waiting in the police station ,
you can leave it directly you 're inside .
There 's a secret way out through the inspector 's private house .
We 'll disguise you as a policeman ,
and you can walk out with other uniformed men and drive away .
Even if he sees you , he won 't recognize you .
He 'll most probably be waiting in front to break in at 10 : 00 .
What happens to me then ?
I 'll have you driven back quietly to this house by the back lanes .
Then get into your car and drive away into the country .
Miles away . And stay there until you heard we 've got him .
Now you needn 't be afraid . We 'll get him all right this time .
I 'll lay traps that even an invisible man can 't pass .
You see , it covers a fairly wide range .
I 've got 20 of these guns and a good man to each .
One splash of this on his skin ,
and we 've got something to follow at last .
Why not paint the top of the wall ?
Because he 'd smell it .
I 've got a better plan .
I 'm going to put a thin layer of loose earth along the top of the wall .
The slightest touch will disturb it , and we 've got him trapped .
Oh , I see . Pretty good .
Forward . Quick , march !
They think they 're very clever .
All right , take him straight inside .
Twenty minutes to 10 : 00 . Keep your eyes open now , boys .
Here , quick , sir . I heard footsteps outside .
Soft footsteps , like naked feet .
Listen .
( ENGINE RUNNING )
MAN : All ready . Come on .
Where are you going to ?
In the mountains , 100 miles away .
Drive away quickly .
Well ... It 's ten minutes to 10 : 00 .
He 's bound to do something any minute .
Do you suppose he 'll try getting in through the station ?
Every door and window is barred , with a double guard on each .
He 'll try the wall right enough .
There he goes ! There !
To your stations now . Watch the wall .
He 's over the wall . I felt breathing down my neck .
He 's in here !
10 : 00 ! 10 : 00 he wanted to murder me !
JACK : I think this 'll do nicely , Kemp . We 'll stop here .
It 's 10 : 00 . I came with you to keep my promise .
( BELL TOLLING )
No ! It 's all a mistake , Griffin .
I swear , I never told the police .
I want to help you . Let me be your partner .
I 've had a cold and uncomfortable journey
just to keep my promise at 10 : 00 .
I went into the police station with you , Kemp .
I stood by while you changed into that coat .
I rode on the running board of the car that took you home again .
( GASPING )
( CHOKING )
( GRUNTING )
I know that I could never tell who you are . Who are you ?
There . You sit there . I 've got you where I want you .
JACK : I hope your car 's insured , Kemp .
I 'm afraid there 's going to be a nasty accident in a minute .
A very nasty accident .
Listen , I 'll do anything , everything you ask me .
You will ? That 's fine .
Just sit where you are . I 'll get out and take the hand brake off
and give you a little shove to help you on .
You 'll run gently down and through the railings .
You 'll have a big thrill for 100 yards or so till you hit a boulder .
Then you 'll do a somersault and probably break your arms .
Then a grand finish-up with a broken neck .
Well , good-bye , Kemp . I always said you were a dirty little coward .
You 're a dirty , sneaking little rat as well . Good-bye .
( JACK LAUGHING )
( KEMP SCREAMING )
A thousand replies have come to my appeal
for suggesting ways of catching the Invisible Man .
Some are clever , some stupid , but all are impossible .
He 's got to sleep . They might catch him asleep .
He 's got to eat and drink .
A cafe was robbed last night in Manton .
There 's no proof he did it .
There are robberies every night by ordinary burglars .
( JACK SIGHS )
This feels good .
( SNEEZING )
( JACK SNORING )
( RUSTLING )
( SNORING CONTINUES )
Look there ! We wanted help . There it is .
It 's now or never . Snow won 't lie long at this time of year .
It may be gone in a few hours .
Find out if the snow is general over the country .
Send out a broadcast message .
He can 't stay out in this bitter cold . He 'll seek shelter .
Excuse me , sir . There 's breathing in my barn .
What do you mean , breathing in your barn ?
The Invisible Man , sir , sure as I stand here .
The farmer may have imagined it ,
but we can 't leave anything to chance .
Surround the barn . No use trying to take him on the inside .
Force him out into the snow .
Take a pile of wood and gasoline and set fire to it .
( ALL CHATTERING )
That 's it , sir . He 's in there under a pile of straw , sir .
Are there any windows he can watch from ?
No , sir . Only the door , sir .
( JACK MOANING )
There 's a reward of £ 1 , 000 waiting for you if we 're successful .
That 's the place , and we 're lucky to have the open country .
Take your men over to the line of trees
and cover the country from the road to the top of the hill .
Line the ridge through those trees , double .
Now , Chief . There 's no time to lose .
We can 't wait till he comes out to search for food .
We must fire the barn at once and drive him out into the snow .
You men , keep in single file .
We don 't want a lot of your footprints around the barn .
We want to keep the snow for his feet alone .
Get that searchlight on the door of that barn .
He 's out ! Look !
Shall I give the signal to advance ?
( GUNSHOTS )
I don 't think your guard will be needed any longer .
How is he ?
He 's very near the end .
Are you Dr. Cranley ?
Yes . I had a message to come immediately .
Towards dawn this morning , he grew quiet .
He called the name of a girl . I understand your daughter , Dr. Cranley .
She 's waiting below . ls there any chance ?
Bullet passed through both lungs .
It 's impossible to treat the wound .
Do you think your daughter could bear to go to him ?
I 'm afraid the end may be rather terrible .
The effect of the drugs will die with him .
His body will become visible as life goes .
I 'll bring her now .
JACK : ls Flora there ?
She 's coming now .
I knew you would come to me , Flora .
I wanted to come back to you .
My darling ,
I failed .
I meddled in things
that man must leave alone .
( JACK GROANS )
Father , come quickly !